

LOTELENI (KAUKO) SHIKULO

GEO INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - SPECIALIST

lkshikulo@gmail.com 0814667320

linkedin.com/in/loteleni-shikulo-177922182

SKILLS

Project Management

Systems Evaluation

Service Orientation

Data Capturing, Management, Analysis and Visualizations

Computer Aided Drawing

Geodatabases, PostgreSQL, SQL and Oracle

Remote Sensing

Digital/Web Cartography

MS Office Suite(Excel and Access)

Graphic Design

Organisational Skill

Time Management

QUALITIES

- Integrity
- Willingness to learn
- Analytical Thinking
- Innovation
- Collaborative
- Solution-oriented

PROFILE

She is well experienced in spatial data management, IT, GIS (ArcGIS Pro, QGIS), CSEntery and AutoCAD skills. Additionally, she is detail-oriented, a thoughtful communicator with the ability to solve problems both independently and as part of a team. She has a keen interest in GIS for resources management, renewable energy and Agripreneurship, thus she would like to learn and improve her data analysis and manipulation skills in these industries. As a fast learner, she is able to quickly grasp new concepts to fill knowledge gaps to contribute diligently and competitively to your company's continuous success.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Geoinformation Technology

Feb 2019 - Dec 2022

Namibia University of Science and Technology, Windhoek

- Three years of experience in GIS knowledge of various methods for describing the location and distribution of land, water, and mineral deposits.
- Strong skills in Remote Sensing, Data (Geoinformation) Management, Visualization, Surveying, GIS mapping and Imagery & Spatial Analysis.
- Completed a "Flood Risk Assessment for Ohangwena region" internship (Work Integrated Learning) project.
- Three years of experience in computer operating systems and applications
- Good experience using ESRI's ArcGIS Desktop software suite, Quantum GIS, SNAP
- Knowledge of CAD design, Web/ Digital Cartography
- Experience with Software Engineering, Web Development, and Information Competency
- Experience with Geodemographic analysis and survey generation for data collections.
- Experience with Data Cleaning, Data administration GIS/ Python Programming

EMPLOYMENT

PROFFESSIONAL GIS INTERN -**DERMOGRAPHIC SURVEYOR**

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

Ministry of Agriculture, Water and Land Reform (MAWLR), Windhoek

- Conducting a demographic survey for the Namibia Water Sector Support Program in the Omaheke Region - Otjombinde Water Supply Scheme, as well as using extensive geospatial methods, mappings and data requirements to conduct demographic survey with a GPS device and a Census and Survey Processing System (CSEntry Software)
- Collaborating with other GIS experts to create polished, high-level demographic designs, as well as survey site report documentations.
- Demographic survey consultations

GIS INTERN (FREELANCER)

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

Odikwa Investment CC, Windhoek

- Experience working with ArcGIS, QGIS and GIS databases including, (geo) database creation, organizing and management. Experience working with a variety of GISrelated datasets and data formats (CSV, XLS, Shapefiles).
- Experience with geoprocessing analyses and spatial statistics analyses of geology data maps generation.

DATA CLERK (CONSULTANT)

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

IntraHealth Namibia, Windhoek

- Received and entered accurately the KP PREV data into a database.
- Maintained database by entering new and updated client information.
- Prepared source data for computer entry by compiling, verifying the accuracy and sorting information. Reviewing data for deficiencies or errors, correcting any incompatibilities, and checking output.

INTERESTS

- Resources management
- Research
- Agripreneurship
- Renewable Energy Technologies
- Data Science and Robotics
- Earth Science

HOBBIES

- Acquiring new skills
- Networking
- Field work
- Volunteer
- Photography
- Writting

CURRENT RESEARCH

I am collaborating with other young researchers from Cameroon and Algeria on a research proposal inspired by green hydrogen and its role in a low-carbon future, Challenges and Opportunities for Africa.

LANGUAGES

English

Oshiwambo

Otjiherero

REFERENCES

1. Mr Dirk Jones Coetzee, Project Engineer
Ministry of Agriculture, Water and Land Reform, Windhoek
061 208 7328,
Dirk.Coetzee@mawlr.gov.na

- 2. Mr Sebastian Mukumbira, Data Analyst Windhoek +264 81 279 0059, sabam976@gmail.com
- 3. Mrs. Mary Barton, Consultant Odikwa Investment CC, Windhoel +264 81 1470381, odikwa@gmail.com

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Founder / Chief Networking Officer

Jan 2022 - Present

The Young to Young (Ltd), Windhoek

Currently responsible for overlooking all the internal and external activities of the company at the local and the international level.

Assistant Leader-Namibia:

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

Judyspiration Peace Channel, Windhoek

Facilitated a global webinar on peace awareness "Humanity the key to the world's infinite Peace" and assisted the president in the documentation of the platform

Device Setter and Tester

Jan 2021 - Jun 2021

SE Tracker 2 Project, Windhoek

Working in setting up and testing the Geofenced enabled children tracking devices, translated requirements into high-level designs, set up the devices for GPS receptions and tracking, and compiled product's user manual documentation

Secretary-General / Vice President

Jun 2020 - Nov 2021

Muhoko @NUST Society, Windhoek

Administered and kept documentation, and meetings minutes compiled programs and progress reports and administered the membership recruitment drives of the society.

Director of Community Development

Jan 2018 - Nov 2021

Young Africans Network for Global Goals, Windhoek

Hosted international webinar on community development related issues such as sustainable innovation

Managed and directed planning and management initiatives for the organization

CERTIFICATES

| Game Design and Computer-Aided Design (CAD) - Digital Transformation Center Namibia | Mar 2022 |
|---|----------|
| Innovation and System Logic Certificate - IBS | May 2022 |
| Google Analytics for Beginners Certificate - IBS | May 2022 |
| 7th SGA Short Course on African Metallogeny 2021, Energy for Sustainable Society | Nov 2021 |
| Workforce Collaboration and Development- Young African Leadership Initiative - YALI | Sep 2020 |
| Strategic Organizational Leadership (Master Class) - IBS | Oct 2020 |
| Digital Transformation and Future for Work- International Business School Americas | Dec 2020 |
| Management Strategies for People and Resources- YALI | Sep 2020 |
| Project Management Tools - IBS | Oct 2022 |

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. 2nd Best Winner of "The Namibian" National Newspaper's Ethical Hackathon Competition for the year 2022.
- 2. Nominated as World Peace advocates for 2020.
- 3. Top 30 winner and published a case study for Zoom Corp through the International Business School Americas in 2020.
- 4. Participated in the **#SheLeadsSeries programme hosted by YANGGs** of 2021.
- Won the international Game Jam+ competition with a game titled "Ewangandjo" hosted in Brazil in 2020.
- 6. Hosted a music coding project, Sonic PI through the Wiscie girl, Google, Intel, NASA, GirlUp, NUST and the U.S. State Department in 2019.